Contact

nicole.twine@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nicole-twine-phd-aprn-acnp-bc-ne-bc-7b75b526 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Critical Care

ICU

Neurosurgery

Certifications

Nurse Executive

Acute Care Nurse Practitioner

Nicole Twine, PhD, APRN, ACNP-BC, NE-BC

Vice President and Chief Nursing Officer Houston Methodist Willowbrook Hospital

Houston, Texas

Summary

Effective, self-motivated health care executive with demonstrated skills and proven success in developing and implementing strategies; planning, organizing, directing and managing current operations. Responsible for development and implementation of key strategtic initiatives while assiting other healthcare leaders. Experienced in hospital operations and nursing leadership. Provides a hands on managmement style with the ability to partner, build relationships, lead and motivate others.

Experience

Houston Methodist

8 years 2 months

Vice President and Chief Nursing Officer Houston Methodist Willowbrook

March 2020 - Present (3 months)

Associate Chief Nursing Officer Houston Methodist-TMC October 2018 - March 2020 (1 year 6 months)

Director of the Nurse Practitioner Service February 2014 - March 2020 (6 years 2 months)

Manager of the Nurse Practitioner Service April 2012 - February 2014 (1 year 11 months)

Texas Woman's University
Faculty/ Graduate Teaching Assistant
September 2015 - September 2019 (4 years 1 month)

Faculty in NP Role Transition course

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston (UTHealth)

Acute Care Nurse Practitioner April 2006 - June 2013 (7 years 3 months)

Work for the Department of Neurosurgery

ACNP as a part of a Level 1 Neurotrauma Intensivist team

Memorial Hermann Health System
Acute Care Nurse Practitioner
February 2007 - February 2010 (3 years 1 month)

ACNP in the CVICU as a part of the Pulmonary Critical Care Intensivist team

Memorial Hermann Health System Critical Care Registered Nurse January 1997 - April 2005 (8 years 4 months)

Education

Texas Woman's University

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Nursing Science · (2012 - 2018)

The University of Texas Medical Branch Masters of Science, Nursing (2005)

The University of Texas Medical Branch BSN, Nursing · (2003 - 2004)

North Harris Montgomery Community College Associate of Applied Science, Nursing (2001)

Sam Houston State University (1992 - 1994)